# **Aniket Pradhan**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

📕 +91 98975 00297 | 💌 aniketpradhan1999@gmail.com | 🥻 aniket-pradhan.github.io | 🖸 github.com/Aniket-Pradhan | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/ap9989

#### Personal Profile

A nerd working at Adobe, as a Software Development Engineer. Currently working on the Streaming workflows in the Adobe Experience Platform, to segment billions of different "profiles" within minutes. Zealous about Research and Development, with a few publications at major conferences around Optical Network Communication. Fascinated by Machine Learning and Data Engineering roles.

### **Education**

#### Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Delhi, India

B. Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

Aug 2017 - May 2021

• Courses: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Speech Recognition and Understanding, Game Design and Development, Software Development using Open Source, Digital Audio, Digital Image Recognition

Father Agnel School

Delhi, India

High School 2015 - 2017

- Passed with Distinction
- Specialised in Physics, Chemistry, and Maths with Computer Science

### Work Experience

Adobe Noida, India

Software Development Engineer

Jul 2021 - Present

- · Collaborated with a small team to work on different Streaming workflows, responsible for segmenting user profiles in real-time
- Took ownership of multiple small projects that aid the Streaming workflows
- Technical Skills: Java, Scala, Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Apache Flink, Microsoft Azure Cosmos DB, Kubernetes, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Ownership, Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

Adobe Noida, India

Product Intern May 2020 - July 2020

- Worked with the Digital Experience team @ Adobe
- · Worked on a closed domain question and answering framework, using the state of the art methods of natural language processing methods.
- Designed to be flexible and modular. Suitable for Adobe Experience Platform's Documentation
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow and PyTorch XLA (for Google TPU), Git.
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

RealVolNew Delhi, IndiaUI Designer InternMay 2018 – July 2018

· Worked on the design and the UI for the product, RealVol

• Technical Skills: Unity VR, C#, Git.

• Soft Skills: Time Management, Communication.

DECEMBER 1, 2022

Noida, India

Android Developer Intern

June 2018 – July 2018

- · Created and implemented simple animations for Android.
- Implemented scalable widgets for Android Applications.
- Technical Skills: Android Studio, Java, Kotlin
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Communication.

## **University Projects**

#### **Efficient Filling of C+L Bands for an Optical Network**

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Insitute of Information Technology - Delhi and British Telecom

May 2019 - May 2020

- Studying the non-linear effects faced by the optical signal in a multi-hop path.
- Analyzing link margins in an optical network and studying the methods to reduce them in a backbone optical network.
- Comparing the benefits offered by a multi-fiber optical network and a multi-band optical network.
- Technical Skills: Python, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

#### Deep Neural Network Based Predictions of Protein Interactions using Primary Sequences

Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Oct. 2018 - Feb. 2019

- · Written a tool in Python to automate data collection and organize the data in a pretty SQL table.
- Worked on and implemented Deep Structured Semantic Network (DSSM) in Python using Tensorflow
- Worked on an approach to simplify querying of similarity based protein sequences, using supervised methods
- Technical Skills: Python with Tensorflow, SQL.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

IoT Smart Lock Delhi, India

Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology - Delhi

Dec. 2017 - Apr. 2018

- Automated lock, which can be controlled securely via the Internet.
- Provides a key less access to the lock, with a robust and modular tech stack.
- Secure communications between the clients and the host, using TLS 1.2
- It was a part of the Introduction to Engineering Development course.
- Technical Skills: C, Python, Arduino.
- Soft Skills: Report writing, Product Design, Logical Thinking.

#### **Publications**

- T. Ahmed, S. Rahman, A. Pradhan et al, "C to C+L Bands Upgrade with Resource Re-provisioning in Optical Backbone Networks", 2021 Optical Fiber Communications Conference and Exhibition (OFC), 2021, pp. 1-3.
- R K. Jana, A. Mitra, A. Pradhan et al, "When Multiband Elastic Optical Networks Becomes More Economical Than Multifiber Elastic Optical Networks?", European Conference on Optical Communication 2020, DOI: 10.1109/ECOC48923.2020.9333276
- A. Mitra, D. Semrau, N. Gahlawat, A. Pradhan et al, "Capacity Benefits of Operation Over C+L Band Elastic Optical Network in the Indian Network Scenario", IEEE ANTS 2019, DOI: 10.1109/ANTS47819.2019.9117992

#### Posters\_

 A. Sinha, A. Pradhan, Q. Fang et al, "Comp-NeuroFedora, a Free/Open Source operating system for computational neuroscience: download, install, research", Org. for Computational Neurosciences 2020

#### Skills\_

**Programming** Java, Scala, Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, NumPy, Pandas etc.), C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

**Miscellaneous** Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), Apache Kafka, Apache Spark, Apache Flink, Łage, Git.

**Soft Skills** Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

DECEMBER 1, 2022 2

# **Positions of Responsibilty**

- 2020 **Byld Admin**, Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2019 **Web Admin**, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2019 **Volunteer**, Summer Camp @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- 2018 **Web Admin**, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi
- **Event Head**, Student Breakthrough, Research Showcase @ Indraprastha Institute of Information 2018
- Technology Delhi
- 2018 **Event Head**, RoboWars, ESYA @ Indraprastha Institute of Information Technology Delhi

### **Languages**

English Professional proficiencyHindi Native proficiencyFrench Bilingual proficiency

DECEMBER 1, 2022 3